Guide to the Edward C. Klostermeyer Papers 1947-1980
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Edward C. Klostermeyer Papers
1947-1980
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 526
Klostermeyer, Edward C.
4 containers. 2 linear feet of shelf space.
Materials about his teaching and research. Includes two films of research on bees which he produced.
Edward C. Klostermeyer, professor of entomology and entomologist, earned his B.S. (1940) and M.S. (1942) at the University of Nebraska, engaged in additional study at the University of California, Berkeley, and earned his Ph.D at WSU in 1952. He joined the WSU faculty in 1947 at the Irrigation Experiment Station in Prosser, and came to Pullman in 1975 as Professor of entomology and entomologist. His areas of research specialization include insect pollination of alfalfa and tree fruits with solitary bees, control of insects attacking field crops, insect transmission of plant diseases and insect ecology. He authored and co-authored many published articles on entomology and produced two films related to his research on bees. He served as president of the Washington State Entomological Society and was a member of the Entomological Society of America. He also was affiliated with Alpha Zeta, agriculture honorary society and Sigma Xi, honorary scientific research society. Three times during his WSU career, he served as acting chairman of the Department Department of Entomology. He retired in 1981.
The papers of Edward Klostermeyer consist of materials about his teaching and research from roughly 1947-1980.
The papers follow the filing system used by Mr. Klostermeyer. Related materials are grouped in individual folders, and visual material is placed at the end of the sequence.
This collection is open for research use.
The papers of Edward Klostermyer were donated to the Washington State University Libraries by Mr. Klostermeyer in 1981 (MS81-27).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Klostermeyer, Edward C. --Archives
Bee culture -- Research
Science; Agriculture; Washington (State)
Entomologists -- Washington (State)--Correspondence
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Resume and photograph of Klostermeyer (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Reprints of Klostermeyer's published papers, 1942-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Talks, awards and misc., 1951-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Seed production short course, 1966; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Seed production short course, 1971; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Short course for flyers, field men and managers, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence on Horace Telford's replacement and Ag. Ent. courses, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- First annual Northwest Legume Seed Growers School-- College of Idaho, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Course outlines and evaluation, Ag.201, Ent.452, 340, Ent.560, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Course outlines and evaluation, Ent.450, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous --chiefly relative to Klostermeyer's appointment at WSU, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Teaching Ent.443 (Insect Ecology)--Responses and evaluations, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Entomology Society of America--Teaching Award Committee, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Pest management curriculum, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Entomology Annual Report--Irrigation Experiment Station, Prosser, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Entomology Annual Reports, 1947-1954 (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
- 50th anniversary of Irrigated Agriculture Research and Extension Center, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
- Materials from Pacific Northwest Vegetable Insect Conference, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- RE. Reasearch grant from NSF for Klostermeyer's research project--sex control in the Leafcutting Bee, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Leafcutters--mason bee, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Alfalfa seed pest management, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Pestcide recommendations and policy, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Alfalfa weevils, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Mite control on corn, 1958-1973 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Greenbug, problems and survey, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Cutworm, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Mint insect control, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Billbugs, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Photographs (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Negatives related to research (Box 3, Folder 33)
- 26th annual meeting of Biological Photographic Association, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Film by Klostermeyer--Her Home Is a Hole--responses, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Films: The Orchard Mason Bee (Box 4)
- Films: Her Home Is a Hole (Box 4)
- Slides (Box 4)